<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<root version="5.1" dataversion="20260124" release="18|CoreRPG:7">
	<npc>
		<ac type="string">35 (-1 size, +5 Dex, +21 natural), touch 14, flat-footed 30</ac>
		<advancement type="string">23-33 HD (Large); 34-66 HD (Huge)</advancement>
		<alignment type="string">Always good (any)</alignment>
		<atk type="string">+5 dancing greatsword +35 melee (3d6+18/19-20) or +2 composite longbow, mighty 5 +28 ranged (2d6+7/x3 plus slaying) or slam +30 melee (2d8+13)</atk>
		<babgrp type="string">+22/+35</babgrp>
		<charisma type="number">25</charisma>
		<constitution type="number">20</constitution>
		<cr type="number">23</cr>
		<dexterity type="number">20</dexterity>
		<environment type="string">Any good-aligned plane</environment>
		<feats type="string">Cleave, Dodge, Great Cleave, ImprovedInitiative, Improved Sunder, Mobility, Power Attack, Track</feats>
		<fortitudesave type="number">18</fortitudesave>
		<fullatk type="string">+5 dancing greatsword +35/+30/+25/+20 melee (3d6+18/19-20) or +2 composite longbow, mighty 5 +28/+23/+18/+13 ranged (2d6+7/x3 plus slaying) or slam +30 melee (2d8+13)</fullatk>
		<hd type="string">22d8+110</hd>
		<hp type="number">209</hp>
		<init type="number">9</init>
		<intelligence type="number">23</intelligence>
		<leveladjustment type="string"> - </leveladjustment>
		<librarylink type="windowreference">
			<class>npc</class>
			<recordname>..</recordname>
		</librarylink>
		<locked type="number">1</locked>
		<name type="string">Angel, Solar (Copy)</name>
		<organization type="string">Solitary or pair</organization>
		<reflexsave type="number">18</reflexsave>
		<skills type="string">Concentration +30, Craft or Knowledge (any five) +33, Diplomacy +34, Escape Artist +30, Hide +26, Listen +32,Move Silently +30, Search +31, Sense Motive +32, Spellcraft +31, Spot +32, Survival +7 (+9 following tracks), Use Rope +5 (+7 with bindings)</skills>
		<spacereach type="string">10 ft./10 ft.</spacereach>
		<specialattacks type="string">Spell-like abilities, spells</specialattacks>
		<specialqualities type="string">Damage reduction 15/epic and evil, darkvision 60 ft., low-light vision, immunity to acid, cold, and petrification, protective aura, regeneration 15 (epic and evil or spell and evil), resistance to electricity 10 and fire 10, spell resistance 32, tongues</specialqualities>
		<speed type="string">50 ft. (10 squares), fly 150 ft. (good)</speed>
		<spelldisplaymode type="string">action</spelldisplaymode>
		<spellset />
		<strength type="number">28</strength>
		<text type="formattedtext">
			<p>Angels are a race of celestials, beings who live on the good-aligned Outer Planes.</p>
			<p>Angels can be of any good alignment. Regardless of their alignment, angels never lie, cheat, or steal. They are impeccably honorable in all their dealings and often prove the most trustworthy and diplomatic of all the celestials.</p>
			<p>All angels are blessed with comely looks, though their actual appearances vary widely.</p>
			<p>Angels speak Celestial, Infernal, and Draconic, though they can speak with almost any creature because of their tongues ability.</p>
			<p>A solar has a deep and commanding voice, and stands about 9 feet tall. It weighs about 500 pounds.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Combat</b>
			</p>
			<p>In combat, most angels make full use of their mobility and their ability to attack at a distance.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Angel Traits: </b>An angel possesses the following traits (unless otherwise noted in a creature's entry).</p>
			<list>
				<li>Darkvision out to 60 feet and low-light vision.</li>
				<li>Immunity to acid, cold, and petrification.</li>
				<li>Resistance to electricity 10 and fire 10.</li>
				<li>+4 racial bonus on saves against poison.</li>
				<li>
					<i>Protective Aura (Su): </i>Against attacks made or effects created by evil creatures, this ability provides a +4 deflection bonus to AC and a +4 resistance bonus on saving throws to anyone within 20 feet of the angel. Otherwise, it functions as a <i>magic circle against evil </i>effect and a <i>lesser globe of invulnerability, </i>both with a radius of 20 feet (caster level equals angel's HD). This aura can be dispelled, but the angel can create it again as a free action on its next turn. (The defensive benefits from the circle are not included in an angel's statistics block.)</li>
				<li>
					<i>Tongues (Su): </i>All angels can speak with any creature that has a language, as though using a <i>tongues </i>spell (caster level equal to angel's Hit Dice). This ability is always active.</li>
			</list>
			<p>Solars are puissant champions of good. Only the most powerful fiends approach their power.</p>
			<p>Even more fearsome than their <i>+5 dancing greatswords </i>are their <i>+2 composite longbows </i>that create any sort of <i>slaying arrow </i>when drawn.</p>
			<p>A solar's natural weapons, as well as any weapons it wields, are treated as good-aligned and epic for the purpose of overcoming damage reduction.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Regeneration (Ex): </b>A solar takes normal damage from epic evil-aligned weapons, and from spells or effects with the evil descriptor.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Spell-Like Abilities: </b>At will - <i>aid, animate objects, commune, continual flame, dimensional anchor, greater dispel magic, holy smite </i>(DC 21), <i>imprisonment </i>(DC 26), <i>invisibility </i>(self only), <i>lesser restoration </i>(DC 19), <i>polymorph </i>(self only) <i>power word stun, remove curse </i>(DC 20), <i>remove disease </i>(DC 20), <i>remove fear </i>(DC 18), <i>resist energy, summon monster VII, speak with dead </i>(DC 20) <i>, waves of fatigue </i>; 3/day - <i>blade barrier </i>(DC 23), <i>earthquake </i>(DC 25), <i>heal </i>(DC 23), <i>mass charm monster </i>(DC 25), <i>permanency, resurrection, waves of exhaustion </i>; 1/day - <i>greater restoration </i>(DC 24), <i>power word blind </i>, <i>power word kill </i>, <i>power word stun, prismatic spray </i>(DC 24), <i>wish </i>. Caster level 20th. The save DCs are Charisma-based.</p>
			<p>The following abilities are always active on a solar's person, as the spells (caster level 20th): <i>detect evil, detect snares and pits, discern lies </i>(DC 21), <i>see invisibility, true seeing </i>. They can be dispelled, but the solar can reactivate them as a free action.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Spells: </b>Solars can cast divine spells as 20th-level clerics. A solar has access to two of the following domains: Air, Destruction, Good, Law, or War (plus any others from its deity). The save DCs are Wisdom-based.</p>
			<p>
				<i>Typical Cleric Spells Prepared </i>(6/8/8/8/7/7/6/6/5/5; save DC 17 + spell level): 0 - <i>create water, detect magic, guidance </i>(2), <i>resistance </i>(2); 1st - <i>bless </i>(2), <i>cause fear, divine favor </i>(2), <i>entropic shield, obscuring mist </i>*, <i>shield of faith; </i>2nd - <i>align weapon, bear's endurance </i>(2), <i>bull's strength </i>(2), <i>consecrate, eagle's splendor, spiritual weapon </i>*; 3rd - <i>daylight, invisibility purge, magic circle against evil, magic vestment </i>*, <i>prayer </i>(2), <i>protection from energy, wind wall; </i>4th - <i>death ward </i>(2), <i>dismissal </i>(2), <i>divine power </i>*, <i>neutralize poison </i>(2); 5th - <i>break enchantment, control winds </i>*, <i>dispel evil, plane shift, righteous might </i>(2), <i>symbol of pain; </i>6th - <i>banishment, chain lightning </i>*, <i>heroes' feast, mass cure moderate wounds, undeath to death, word of recall; </i>7th - <i>control weather </i>*, <i>destruction, dictum, ethereal jaunt, holy word, regenerate; </i>8th - <i>fire storm, holy aura, mass cure critical wounds </i>(2), <i>whirlwind </i>*; 9th - <i>etherealness, elemental swarm (air) </i>* <i>, mass heal, miracle, storm of vengeance </i>.</p>
			<p>*Domain spell. Domains: Air and War.</p>
		</text>
		<token type="token"></token>
		<treasure type="string">No coins; double goods; standard items</treasure>
		<type type="string">Large Outsider (Angel, Extraplanar, Good)</type>
		<willsave type="number">20</willsave>
		<wisdom type="number">25</wisdom>
	</npc>
</root>